# **Anita Torrence**

7512 Berks Way, Hudson, Ohio 44236 518-588-8647 anita.torrence@gmail.com

https://github.com/atorrence https://www.linkedin.com/in/anita-torrence

# **Professional Summary**

Highly organized, detail oriented and self-directed individual with recent certification in C# from Tech Elevator, a comprehensive coding bootcamp. Background includes a degree in Mathematics and specialized training in information management during service as an Air Force officer.

### **Professional Experience**

Tech Elevator - .NET Development Certificate April 2017

- C# Language Fundamentals: variables, data types, loops, conditional statements, exception handling, collections framework, I/O
- Object Oriented Programming: classes and objects, interfaces, access modifiers, class modeling, encapsulation, inheritance, and polymorphism, class diagrams
- Web Application Development: HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, ASP.NET MVC
- Database Programming: ADO.NET, table design and creation, SQL queries and DML, MS SQL, E/R diagrams
- Development tools and techniques: Agile, unit testing (MS Test), TDD, Git command line, Visual Studio 2015, Selenium, Cucumber

Andrews Moving and Storage, Streetsboro, OH 44241 Move Coordinator, Feb 2013 – May 2016

- Single point of contact during the entire moving process for a yearly average of 590 residential moves a year
- Managed the calendars for two residential salesmen to set up new opportunities
- Reviewed estimated costs and planned services with each customer
- Developed process improvements to reduce time spent on recurring procedures
- Earned Move Coordination Certification with a Silver rating during 2014 and 2015

Air Force Material Command, Wright Patterson Air Force Base, Dayton, Ohio 1st Lieutenant, Information Management Officer, Jan 1994 - Jan 1996

- Provided administrative support to the Squadron Section Commander
  - While acting as liaison for the commander, attended briefings and completed summaries for distribution to all departments or led meetings to disseminate information
  - Oversaw the completion of all required health and fitness regulations for 1,300 associates
  - Developed performance evaluation tracking database that included automated reminder notifications to supervising personnel, which when fully implemented covered 10,000 associates
  - Supervised an office of 6 direct reports

56<sup>th</sup> Mission Support Squadron, MacDill Air Force Base, Tampa, Florida 2<sup>nd</sup> Lieutenant, Personnel Officer, Nov 1992 - Jan 1994

- Supervised staff of 11 direct reports responsible for ensuring the maintenance and accuracy of personnel records of 4,000 associates in 10 locations
- Ensured compliance with all governmental policies and regulations
- Successfully implemented global personnel processes that ensured the timely recognition of promotion opportunities and completion of all necessary benefit related documentation

#### **Education**

.NET Development Certificate - Tech Elevator – April 2017 Bachelor of Science in Mathematics - University of Dayton, Ohio

# **Volunteer Experience**

- Hudson Middle School Receptionist/Office Assistant and Hudson Schools Library Aid
- PTA Chairperson and After School Enrichment Teacher, Karigon Elementary, Clifton Park, NY
- Team Manager and League Representative, Clifton Park Soccer Club, Clifton Park, NY
- President, Mothers and More, Lake Norman, North Carolina chapter